Full Stack Web Developer

Career summary

An experienced web developer with a strong background in PHP, MySQL and JavaScript. Irini has a 5 years experience in developing services for both car-rental industry and property management systems. Furthermore she has a strong background in computational mathematics and algorithmic complexity, which makes her ideal for facing problems on large-scale networks. She is currently working in a group of companies: Surprice, LeaderStay, ExperTaste

Work experience

Surprice Car Rentals, LeaderStay & ExperTaste WEB DEVELOPER

Jan 2012 - Present

- Designing, coding and testing of a fleet management environment.
- Developing and maintenance of a custom CMS.
- Data analysis and representation.
- Designing, coding and testing of the booking platform.
- Developing and expansion of our own web service.
- Integrating as a client with other web services.
- Optimization of database structure and its functions.
- Finding and applying solutions in algorithmic complexity challenges.
- Investigating, fixing and debugging software defects.
- Specifying and prioritizing of system changes according to the clients requirements.
- Development of a sales web application used by ExperTaste with a mobile first approach

ICS-FORTH BioMedicine Laboratory

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jan 2007 - Dec 2011

Managed research activities focused on visualization and pattern recognition on complex networks.

University of Crete

UNDERGRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

Oct 2004 - Jul 2008

- Data Structures (2008)
- Discrete Mathematics (2008)
- Applied Mathematics I (2005 2006)
- Calculus II (2004)

Academic qualifications

University of Crete 2006 – 2010

BSc Computer Science

University of Crete 2007 – 2009

MSc Mathematical Foundation of Computer Science

Thesis: "Construction of Surrounding Curves for Convex Polygonal Objects using Voronoi Diagrams"

University of Crete 2002 – 2006

BSc Applied Mathematics

Good performance award Sep 2006

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Code quality
- Debugging/Problem solving
- Testing
- Time planning
- · Responsive design
- Algorithmic complexity optimization

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Strong skills in PHP (Procedural or Object Oriented), JavaScript/jQuery, SQL, CSS, XHTML, HTML, C
- Web service creation (SOAP with XML output)
- Connection to web services (XML/JSON)
- Understanding and compliance with OWASP
- Version control (Git/GitHub)
- Less/Sass,
- GIMP, Photoshop
- Use of task runners (Grunt, Gulp)
- AngularJS, Java, C++, JSP, Matlab

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Able to work on my own or in a team.
- Good time management/prioritization skills.
- Ability to follow complex instructions.
- · Critical thinking.
- Attention to detail.
- Clear and effective communication skills
- High sense of honesty and dependability.

LANGUAGES

- Greek Native tongue
- English Proficient
- French Basic understanding

HOBBIES/INTERESTS

- Ashtanga Yoga
- Sailing

REFERENCES

Available on request.

CONTACT DETAILS

Irini Koutaki Pantermaki Raftopoulou 75, Heraklion Crete 71305 Greece

Tel: 0030 6932006661

Email: irinikp@protonmail.com

www.irinikp.com